[Music]
If you haven't been vi coding enough,
you must have experienced problem where
you ask cursor to implement a small
change but just map up your whole
project or cursor is not aware of all
the dependencies in your codebase and
implement something that leads to loads
of errors. This is a very common issue
of AI coding agent in general no matter
which platform you're using. But there's
one technique that show promising
improvements that will make your cursor
make way less errors, which is giving
your AI coding agent a task management
system. It helps it to understand
overall implementation plan and also
control the amount of context goes into
each step when it is implementing
specific tasks. I was able to build a
fully functional multiplayer online
drawing game where both players can draw
image of given work and we send the
result to GBD4 where it look at image
and give evaluation and pick up the
winner. And this whole game is actually
imprinted by cursor with just one shot
without much arrow which is absolutely
insane. That's why today I want to show
you what my workflow is and how can you
adopt it for your own project. And
before you use any of those tools I just
introduced people has been hacking
together task management workflow to
improve performance for a while. At its
core it basically means you ask cursor
to break down your complex PRD into
small tasks and have a document where
cursor can have access to to track and
maintain what tasks are coming and what
tasks already been done. And this is a
quick example from Elle. The most basic
implementation is in your cursor project
you will create a cursor rule and it
looks something like this. Basically
rule where you tell cursor to always
refer to task.md to keep track about
what task they already been done and
what task haven't. And with this one we
can just create a task.md file and give
a prompt I want to build a x app help me
breaking down into small task of our
core me feature and add to task.md. So
cursor will create a list of task here
and after cursor finish every single
task it will just come back and mar
those task as completed. So it has a
context of overall implementation plan.
With this method it already help a ton
for executing complex task with cursor.
But tools like cloud taskmaster and
boomeran task from ruk code bring even
more sophisticated task management
behavior into the AI coding agents. For
example, for task master AI, it is a
command line package that you can run in
cursor windsurf data where it utilize
cloud 3.7 or more advanced model to look
at PRD you have and break that down into
small subtasks by running a simple
command line like taskmaster parse PRD.
And what's really amazing about it is
that it will breaking down tasks in
logical order consider all the
dependencies between different tasks. So
you won't have situation where cursor
implements something but require other
dependencies that hasn't been
implemented yet. It also has useful
command line like analyze complexities
to use perplexity and cloud to analyze
how complicated each task is and if
certain task complexity score is very
high it will allow you to expand on
those task further and by breaking down
those complex tasks into even smaller
bits. The success rate of it delivering
a functional application just increase
dramatically. And Roco's boomeran task
also something similar. It gives AI
agents tools like new tasks to breaking
down a complex project into small bits
and keep track about progress. Those
tools have completely changed my
workflow. So I'm going to quickly take
you through what's my new best practice
vibe coding workflow with those new
tools. But before we dive into that, I
know many of you are trying to build AI
agents for business. But there are many
pitfalls I saw people fell into at
delivering successful production agents.
That's why I want to introduce you to
this research HubSpot did where they
interviewed tons of business and
startups who have been launching AI
agents for the past 12 months to
understand which AI agent use case
actually drove huge amount of business
value and ROI versus ones that sounds
fancy but actually very difficult to
deliver value and which signal customers
are deploying huge amount of budgets to
buy AI agent solution. They include lots
of real world success stories and
articulate those learnings into
frameworks that you can use to build
your next agents from which use cases
more suitable for chatbot versus actual
autopilot agents. How do you determine
which task is best for AI agents versus
more traditional workflow automation as
well as list of common pitfalls that
many other people encounter including
myself when deploying production agents
and best practice of how other people
resolve that like what's the best
practice for you to build integration
into existing systems. This helped bring
a lot of clarities and many mistakes I
personally experienced. So if you're
planning to build agents, I highly
recommend you go and have a read and
this is totally free. I have put a link
in the description below for you to
download. Now let's talk about my new AI
coding workflow with task management
systems. Firstly, let's talk about ru
code's boomer task feature. And if you
don't know ru code, ro code you can
almost consider as a open-source cursor
that live inside visual studio code. It
is totally free to use. All you need to
do is just provide your own entropy key
and then it will just work like any
other AI coding agent that you've been
using. But what's really cool about real
code is that unlike cursor where you
only have a few predefined agent mode,
Ro allow you to create your own modes
like at default they will provide coding
agent architect agent that will help you
do the planning debug agent that help
you figure out where the arrow is. But
you can also build custom modes like
boomer wrench mode where it will be
focusing on planning and breaking down
the plan into smaller manageable pieces.
Think of it like delegating your work to
specialized assistant. Each subtask runs
in its own context. So I can choose a
boomer range mode that I just customized
and then say help me build a to-do app.
At top you can see that it will keep
track about how many token consumption
is as well as total amount of API cost
and it will firstly delegate a planning
task to the architect agent and this
architect agent will have this system
prompt where it will continuously
confirm with me about the requirements
and then it will start planning out the
project breaking down into specific
feature figure out things like user
story key feature components project
structure state management and many
more. So it has a full understanding
about all dependencies between different
functions. I can give feedback in the
middle and once the plan is finished and
breaking down to small tasks, it can
switch to the code mode to start
generating the code and the code agent
will start executing different tasks
based on the plan and then complete the
actual application for me. And you can
see the result here is very high quality
and it even have functionality built in
where the agent will be able to run the
application in the browser, see the
result to automate testing as well. And
with this one, the result already feels
better than what I got out of box from
cursor. But on the other hand, cloud
taskmaster integrate much more deeply
into cursor and wings surfer. First,
let's install the taskmaster AI. You can
open terminal in any folder and do npm
install-g
taskmaster-ai. And once it's finished,
you can run a few different commands.
One will be taskmaster in it. This will
set up the project inside the folder.
So, you can just do taskmaster in it
directly. But I would suggest you set up
the project first. Like if you're
building a nextjs project with chessen,
you can just do this command. And once
it's done, we can do cursor my app.
Inside here, we can do taskmaster in it.
This will ask for the pent name and I'll
just call it my app. Description doesn't
really matter. You can skip all those
stuff and then just let it set things
up. And what will happen now is that on
the left side you firstly see it add a
few cursor rule. Some of them are
generic one like this cursor rule
basically teach cursor how can it add
new cursor rules. So as you go deep into
the implementation you can ask it to
reflect and creating rules about the
mistake it make for example and it will
follow this rules to create the next
cursor rules and this self-improve is
basically the same thing it kind of try
to get cursor to do this proactively and
the step workflow is where it teach
cursor about all the commands it will
need to actually check all the task in
the backlog and if you're using
windserve there will be windserve root
here as well inside the scripts folder
it provide a structure about what does a
prd can look like but the most important
one is that it will have thisv.exam
example file. What you need to do is
swap out this entropic key as well as
proplasticity key here. So entropy is a
model that will be used to break down
your PRD into small tasks and they also
use perlastity to do some research. So
if part of task is using a new package
that just released then it will actually
use perlasty to fetch the latest
developer documents and include those
into the task information. So I
recommend you add both API key here and
once you did that we can start creating
our PRD. There are many different ways
you can create PRDs. If you're in the AI
builder climate building already, you
will have access to tools like tanks
coder the dev where it will help you
generate PRD automatically and fill in
all the gaps for the features that you
might not think of. So if you're already
in the AI build club, you can use this
tool to get the PRD here. But if you
don't have access, you can also just
chat with cursor agent use that to help
you generate PRD. For example, I can
just say help me build an online game
like Scribble, but instead of a human
guess word, it will be large model guess
a word. So each round all users will be
given a same word and they have 60
seconds to draw the image. In the end
all images will be sent to open 4 and
let it choose which image is closest to
the word. Now play the role as the
engineer manager help me think through
what are the core features of
implementing such game and then it will
spit out the core functionalities.
Obviously I can chat back and forth but
once I finish I can just say great now
let's help me build the core MVP
features requirements into prd.txe using
the example uh prd.txe tx as reference
which is what we have uh showing here
and then you will see a prd has been
created with good amount details and I
will accept that. So now since we have
this prd generated the next step we can
use this command taskmaster parse drd to
breaking down this prd into small task
and this is where the power of
taskmaster begin. So I will do this
taskmaster parse prd
scripts/prd.txt. Okay, so I had this
arrow uh just need making sure you
remove this example and let's do it
again. So now it will start creating
task files based on this prd and you
will see here where we have task folder.
It has all the tasks that created from
taskmaster. What we can do is we can do
taskmaster list and this will show you
the list of tasks that it has been
created. What's really cool about
taskmaster task list is on the right
side you can see here's a dependencies
column. So when breaking down tasks, it
will actually list out the task in a
logical order and making sure there are
clear dependencies mapped out. So when
it implement, it can implement in the
right order. Meanwhile, there are also
some pretty useful commands. You have
this command called analyze complexity.
What this will do is that I can do task
master and analyze complexity. This was
basically send all the task I created to
cloud 3.7 as well as perplexity.
Basically ask it to just evaluate how
complicated or how difficult it is to
implement this feature. And once it is
done, I can do taskmaster complexity
report. It will show me the evaluation
of each task and its complexity score.
But what's really useful is for those
complex tasks, it also give you the
prompt that you can copy. At the moment,
you can't really copy this directly. If
the UI just break up, but you can just
copy the first one and go to complexity
report and find the specific ID which is
this one and we can copy the expansion
prompt. So here it generate a prompt
detailed technical implementation of
HTML 5 canva component including drawing
tools input handling across all devices.
So I can just do this and now it
breaking down that specific task into
smaller ones. And as we know once a
complex task breaking down to smaller
one it is more likely to succeed without
any error. And you can continue doing
that um by adding another one for the
task number five. So you get the drill.
Um basically you can do this process
back and forth for a few times until
you're happy with the backlog here. You
can also do things like update as well.
So if later down the row you decide to
like change the plan, you can also do
taskmaster update ID equal to like four
and prompt equal to something like make
sure we use three js. And what will
happen is that once you give this
prompt, it will actually update the
whole plan based on this new instruction
which is really really helpful. But once
it's done, you can do taskmaster list
with subtasks. This will show all
subtask here directly. So it will make
it easier for you to review all the task
here. So that's pretty much it. Once we
done this, you can just go to the cursor
agent and say let's start implementing
the app based on task we created using
taskmaster. Let's check the next most
important task first. So you might have
this arrow here that it is reusing the
wrong command. Uh so I will just tell it
do not use script dev.js use taskmaster
instead. Just go list all task created
and follow the plan. Then it will see
the plan and decide to implement the
first one first. And as it work on the
task, it will also set the status of
this task to be in progress. And here
since I actually turn on the yolo mode
of cursor, which means it didn't ask me
for permission for running any command
lines, I can basically just go drink a
coffee and let it do the work. And as it
complete, it will mark this task as done
and move on to the next one by doing
taskmaster next. But now when you're in
Euro mode, uh I think cursor it will
limit to 25 coursees if you're using the
cloud 3.7, but you can actually put on
Gemini 2.5 Pro Max. This will allow you
to skip this limit and just do like 2002
coursees without any pause here. All
right. So, it's actually pretty crazy.
It just continue executing tasks one up
another and generate a whole bunch of
files, probably a few thousand lines of
code. And let's just run that first. Um,
so I'll do mpm run def. All right. So,
if I try to open this, it has a lobby
building and authentication building.
So, I can give a name, choose avatar,
start playing, and my user has been
created. I can set how much time we have
for drawing the difficulty and whether
it's public game or not. So it's pretty
good. Uh I can create but okay looks
like the actual game inside hasn't been
done yet but it's pretty impressive
about how much it is able to deliver in
just one go. And I can come back to do
task master list with subtasks. So you
can see that it done the uh first four
tasks but it haven't fully finished the
development game run logic into my UI
component. Maybe that's why the actual
game room is not showing up. So I can
ask it continue to implement but you saw
that I had this arrow here and then I
can prompt it now refract the errors you
made and creating new cursor rules to
making sure you don't make those
mistakes again. Now you can see that it
actually adding new cursor rules about
nextjs app router. Uh though for some
reason it didn't actually create content
which is bit weird and accept this one.
So for now I just copy paste manually. I
probably to update cursor rules to
making sure it will be saved properly.
But now I'm going to continue task. Now
let's check what is the next task to
complete to a point where we can do some
quick testing of the drawing. Okay,
after another 15 minutes of it just
doing the task by itself, I got this
game that's kind of fully functional
where I can give it a name, choose my
avatar, start playing and also create a
room called Jason's room. I can set a
timer about how long people can draw as
well as number of runs, the difficulties
and if I create a room other people will
be able to see the room I created as
well. Click on join. We will see
multiple players in the room. And if I
start this, I will have this canva where
people can start drawing to describe
what this uh word is. And on the top
right corner, there's also a timer
document how much time is left. And once
it finish, it will send both result to
chat GPT and GPT will look at the image
and give the description and evaluation,
pick up the winner to get points and
then move on to the next one. So it's
pretty amazing that it did a whole
multiplayers games like this by itself
in 20 minutes. So this how much
performance gain you can get by equip
cursor with the right task management
systems and what's really exciting is
that this is just beginning. I can
imagine those tools and system became
way better in a few months time. I also
interviewed the creator of taskmaster
project where he gave more detailed
breakdown about the best practice
workflow to fully unleash the power of
taskmaster and exciting things that they
are working on right now. If you're
interested, you can join the AI builder
club where I put a full interview and
workflow inside the community for you to
check out as well as bunch other
learnings and tips from industry experts
for both vibe coding and building
production ready AI agents. And you will
also have access to tools like 10x
coderdev where it will help you generate
bulletproof cursor PRD as well as
next.js boplay that already have all
payment backend database set up so you
can launch your SAS in just a weekend. I
post a link in the description below for
you to join if you're interested. I hope
you enjoyed this video. I continue
sharing new tips and workflows I
learned.